<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Revenue | The Face Of IT]]></title>
  <link href="http://TheFaceOfIT.github.io/blog/categories/revenue/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://TheFaceOfIT.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-15T21:10:31-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://TheFaceOfIT.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Devlin Liles]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Face of IT today]]></title>
    <link href="http://TheFaceOfIT.github.io/blog/2013/07/09/the-purpose-of-Face-of-IT/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-09T20:51:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://TheFaceOfIT.github.io/blog/2013/07/09/the-purpose-of-Face-of-IT</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This site is dedicated to resolving some of the core questions surrounding the purpose, usage, and view of IT in the business space today. Questions like&hellip;</p>

<p>Are you in IT and struggle with the concern that business cares more about quantity than quality when it comes to your work?</p>

<p>Are you in business, and struggle to understand what quality is, and how it effects your costs?</p>

<p>These are questions that as an industry we&rsquo;ve struggled needlessly with for decades, because the real question is : <strong>How can rapid, high quality IT effect our ability to generate revenue?</strong></p>

<p>Answering this question with small pragmatic steps is how we are going to change <strong>the face of IT</strong>.</p>

<!-- More -->


<p><a href="#revenue"></a></p>

<h2>Revenue</h2>

<p>Revenue is what drives every business, and IT cannot be ignorant of that.  IT needs to adjust its focus to think of every activity in the light of revenue generation, not revenue neutrality or cost basis.</p>

<p>To many times, IT is handled as a cost.  How can we cut costs, cut schedule, cut features to effect our bottom line.  Think of changing our approach to one like Instagram, where technology changed how we deal with an everyday problem and in under a year created a billion dollar company.  Applied to established industries like Education, Oil &amp; Gas, Insurance, Government, Finance or any many others, how could these approaches revolutionize our businesses and our world.</p>

<p>Here we will present approaches, and guidance, to leverage IT as a fundamental component of your business that will revolutionize your revenue. This guidance is not targeted only toward the technical IT member, or the Business side IT member, but toward everyone involved with developing software solutions to business problems.</p>

<p><a href="#rapid"></a></p>

<h2>Rapid</h2>

<p>When we say Rapid Development, we are talking about one simple idea &ndash; working software in under 30 days.</p>

<p>Over the last 20 years, we have watched as manufacturing has been revolutionized, where products can be envisioned, prototyped, and manufactured in amazingly short cycles, and we are even now on the cusp or removing manufacturing all together, by democratizing this with technologies like 3-D printing.  Software, meanwhile is written nearly the same way it was by the earliest pioneers of business software.  We need to change our mentality from that of large, enterprise software solutions, to small fit to purpose tools that rapidly answer current business needs.</p>

<p>If I were to ask what your current time line to production is, what would you say?  A year?  A month?  With the right approaches, it is easy to quickly deliver complete software in just 30 days.</p>

<p><a href="#quality"></a></p>

<h2>Overall Quality</h2>

<p>In the past 5-10 years our focus as an industry has shifted around. We focused on technical practices with the Test Driven Development and Behavior driven development movements. We then move to the process wars, were our entire focus was agile v. waterfall. We have the chance now to shift that focus again. This time we can make it about quality and the practices that it takes to do well.</p>

<p>Those battles were not waged for naught though.  Only because we have understood quality in the small, through TDD and BDD, and the value of rapid iteration, from our growing understanding of Agile, can we now stand prepared to address overall quality.</p>

<p>While there are many pursuits that relate to overall quality, such as continuous delivery, automated quality testing, and many more, our focus must pragmatically be on quality, and not the by products of these other pursuits.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
